<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Min-Maxing</title>
		<description>Experiments in optimizing web pages, business processes, and life in general.</description>
		<link>http://min-maxing.com</link>
		
			<item>
				<title>Easy Date Range Selection with Qlikview</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;By default, Qlikview allows you to use a date picker or slider object to select dates you can use as ranges to apply to a database field. There are a few problems with this approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slider objects don't allow you to easily select specific dates when you have lots of possible dates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar objects don't allow for easy range selection across multiple months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using list selection boxes can flood the screen with lists of months and years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default, these date ranges will not affect charts based on different date fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, it's easy to set up Qlikview with a more standard &quot;select two dates&quot; widget that will affect all of your charts, regardless of what database date fields drive their display ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/qlikview-calendar-objects.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qlikview calendar date pickers&quot; title=&quot;I want to go to there.&quot; width=&quot;245px&quot; height=&quot;47px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process consists of three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define variables to hold your start and end dates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create calendar widgets that set the values for these variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your charts filter their different database date fields based on the values of these variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How do I set up variables in Qlikview?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 'Settings' menu, there's an item labeled 'Variable Overview...' which will allow you to define variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/qlikview-menu-variable-overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qlikview menu option for variable overview dialog&quot; title=&quot;Access the Variable Overview via the Settings menu option.&quot; width=&quot;248px&quot; height=&quot;137px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking on the menu item, use the 'Add' button to define your variables. For this example, I'll use &lt;mark&gt;vStartDate&lt;/mark&gt; and &lt;mark&gt;vEndDate&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How do I make my date selectors use variables?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 'General' tab of the 'Slider/Calendar Object', you'll see that the 'Data' option is set to 'Field' by default, this causing the object to affect the range of values for the chosen database field. Change this option to 'Variable(s)', then enter the name of one of the two date fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit the ranges a user can select, you can define a minimum and maximum value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/qlikview-calendar-properties-dialog-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qlikview calendar object properties dialog&quot; title=&quot;Properties for the Calendar object in Qlikview&quot; width=&quot;358px&quot; height=&quot;352px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cleanest way to do this is base the minimum and maximum of your start date selector on the minimum and maximum values that your database table holds with the &lt;mark&gt;Min&lt;/mark&gt; and &lt;mark&gt;Max&lt;/mark&gt; functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;=Max(database_field_date)&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the end date selector, base the minimum value on the current value for the start date variable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;=$(vStartDate)&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How do I make my date selectors affect multiple charts?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each chart, go to the 'Expressions' tab in the properties, then click on the 'Definition' field and enter an expression to filter based on the variables your date selectors are now affecting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;=Sum( if( database_field_date &gt;= $(vStartDate) AND database_field_date &lt;= $(vEndDate), ga_visitors) )&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above statement will only select records where the database_field_date is between the two dates picked with the calendar selectors. For only those records, it will sum up the values in the ga_visitors field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can use any other aggregate function you choose. You can, for example, count distinct instances of users based on date ranges as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;=Count( DISTINCT if( database_field2_date &gt;= $(vStartDate) AND database_field2_date &lt;= $(vEndDate), visitor_id) )&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long as the result of this expression is a number, your charts will be able to use it to display the appropriate data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you've updated your charts, you are done! Simply adjust the dates using your selectors and watch as the charts update in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>2012-07-20 00:00:00 -0700</published>
				<link>http://min-maxing.com/blog/2012/07/20/easy-date-range-selection-with-qlikview</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Importing Google Analytics Data into Your Data Warehouse with Pentaho</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Many companies that sell applications and games for desktop and mobile users build a data warehouse so they can create dashboards that show information about user patterns in these applications. By including web funnel data from your website into the data warehouse, you can go a step futher and get complete picture of your user acquisition and retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Data Source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data source is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;. To access the data, we'll need access to the profiles via a username and password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this project, I recommend creating a new Google Analytics account for this project and giving it read-only access to the specific profiles you want to retrieve. Since you'll need to enter this account's password in another piece of software, it's generally a better practice never to use your own accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;ETL Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the data into your data warehouse, you will need software that can extract the data, transform it into the necessary format, then load it into your data warehouse. Such software is called Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) software. For this project, I'll be using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pentaho.com/explore/pentaho-data-integration/&quot;&gt;Pentaho Data Integration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ETL software will need to be able to connect to your data warehouse. You will also need the ability to create new tables and insert/update data into these tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Retrieving &amp;amp; Storing Data with Pentaho&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pentaho comes with a free connector that you can use to query data from Google Analytics. It uses the same syntax as the &lt;a href=&quot;ga-etl-query-ga-transformation.png&quot;&gt;Google Analytics Core Reporting API&lt;/a&gt; to define filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you query Google Analytics, you'll need to grab the following information with the ETL:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A date range&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The filters for each filter step you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we will hard-code the user authentication information, the dimension (time), and metric (visitors).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Job: Master&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-master-job.png&quot; alt=&quot;master Pentaho job for Google Analytics ETL&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: master job for Google Analytics data retrieval&quot; width=&quot;567px&quot; height=&quot;197px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The main thing you should ensure is that the &lt;mark&gt;Get Web Funnel Data&lt;/mark&gt; job is set to execute for every input row on the &quot;Advanced&quot; properties tab. This will cause it to execute for every row that is returned in the previous transformation where we look up the web funnel steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, this job houses little direct logic. The notification emails are helpful if you schedule your ETL to run daily so you know whether or not it succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transformation: Lookup Web Funnel Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-lookup-web-funnel-steps-transformation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho transformation for looking up funnel steps for Google Analytics&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: transformation for retrieving funnel lookup table from the data warehouse&quot; width=&quot;368px&quot; height=&quot;68px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To make the ETL more dynamic, it is helpful to store information about each funnel step in a database table. This will allow you to query for a new step in the future simply by adding a new row to this table. The table schema should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;funnel_step_id&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;auto-incrementing sequence (primary key)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Calling it &quot;funnel_step_id&quot; instead of &quot;id&quot; will make things easier for software that automatically links related tables together&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;String representation of the funnel step for reports.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Example: Landing Page Visitors&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt; 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ga_filter&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;String representation of the filter that Google Analytics will use to execute the query for this funnel step.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Example: ga:eventAction==Start Registration&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Copy Rows to result&quot; output ensures the data is carried over into the next step of the ETL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Job: Get Web Funnel Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-get-web-funnel-data-job.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho job for querying Google Analytics&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: job that manages Google Analytics query&quot; width=&quot;411px&quot; height=&quot;181px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Like the master job, this one has little direct logic. It represents the loop that should execute for each funnel step that is returned from your earlier lookup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transformation: Set Variables for GA Query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-set-variables-transformation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho transformation for getting date and funnel information to set as global variables&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: transformation for getting dynamic date and funnel data to store as global variables&quot; width=&quot;584px&quot; height=&quot;61px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This transformation is responsible for setting up the variables that you will need to feed into the actual query to Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Get rows from result&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this input, you should specify each of the table columns from your lookup table that you'll eventually set as an environment variable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-get-lookup-rows.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog to get rows from previous result&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Get rows from previous result' input dialog&quot; width=&quot;304px&quot; height=&quot;217px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h4&gt;Get Start and End Dates&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Google Analytics sometimes doesn't update their data for 24 hours, you want to be sure you're fetching data for the past few days so you can update days that might have incomplete data. The easiest way to do that is to use the start of last week for your beginning date and yesterday for your end date. This will mean you're always retrieving between 7-14 days of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-get-dates.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for getting system data&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Get System Dialog' input dialog&quot; width=&quot;399px&quot; height=&quot;209px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h4&gt;Scrub Date Fields&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pentaho's date format differs from the format you have to use to query Google Analytics. You can use JavaScript to transform the data into the proper format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;var dateFormat = &quot;yyyy-MM-dd&quot;;

sYesterday = date2str(sYesterday, dateFormat);
sStartLastWeek = date2str(sStartLastWeek, dateFormat);
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterward, make sure you set up the fields to update with the new values in the table below the JavaScript text area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-scrub-dates.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for modifying values with JavaScript&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Script Values / Mod' transformation dialog&quot; width=&quot;609px&quot; height=&quot;448px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h4&gt;Set Global Variables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have all the variables you'll need for the query, make sure you set them with a scope of &quot;Valid in the root job&quot; so that other transformations and jobs have access to the them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-set-vars.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for setting environment variables&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Set Environment Variables' output dialog&quot; width=&quot;454px&quot; height=&quot;261px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h3&gt;Transformation: Query GA and Store Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-query-ga-transformation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho transformation for sending a query to Google Analytics and storing the results&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: transformation for sending the query to Google Analytics and storing the result&quot; width=&quot;366px&quot; height=&quot;67px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the ETL has all the data it needs. All that is left is to execute the query and store the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Get Visitors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter your user credentials, select the appropriate Google Analytics profile, then enter all of the static and variable information as part of your query definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-query-ga.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for getting environment variables&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Google Analytics' input dialog&quot; width=&quot;632px&quot; height=&quot;589px&quot;/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics will return several fields that you do not need. To remove them, select them in the &quot;Output Fields&quot; section, right-click on them, and choose &quot;Delete selected lines&quot; from the menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Get funnel_step_id&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the date and visitor count is part of your result set. You'll need to add the funnel_step_id to the result set so we can link this result to the correct funnel step in your lookup table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-get-funnel-step-id.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for getting environment variables&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Get Variable' input dialog&quot; width=&quot;417px&quot; height=&quot;202px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h4&gt;Insert / Update&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have  the date, funnel step, and visitor count in our result set, we can insert the data into our data warehouse (or update existing rows):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/ga-etl-insert-update.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pentaho dialog for inserting or updating to a database table&quot; title=&quot;Pentaho: 'Insert / Update' output dialog&quot; width=&quot;457px&quot; height=&quot;507px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;In the first table, make sure to specify both the date and the funnel_step_id as the keys to use to look up the values. If Pentaho finds an existing record for that date and funnel_step_id, it will simply update it with the new results rather than add a duplicate entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of my next articles, I will show how you can take the information you have just imported into your data warehouse and create funnel visualizations using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qlikview.com&quot;&gt;QlikView&lt;/a&gt;. This will allow you to connect the dots between all of your funnels and allow you to visualize the end-to-end flow of your users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<published>2012-07-15 00:00:00 -0700</published>
				<link>http://min-maxing.com/blog/2012/07/15/importing-google-analytics-data-into-your-data-warehouse-with-pentaho</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Multi-Channel Funnels in Google Analytics</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;When reviewing the success of your &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#funnel-definition&quot; &gt;funnels&lt;/a&gt;, one way you can &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#segment-definition&quot; &gt;segment&lt;/a&gt; your users is by where they came from when they arrived on your site. This can give you a better idea of which traffic sources are proving valuable to your efforts.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;However, not everyone will perform a key action on their first visit to your site, and it may take some users several visits to reach the end of your primary funnel, and each visit can come from a different source. To assess the value of each of these sources properly, you'll need to understand multi-channel funnels and how to analyze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What are multi-channel funnels?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In marketing parlance, a channel is one avenue via which your site is advertized. How you categorize these sources differs depending on what's important to you, but some general categories for your marketing efforts might include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Display (banner) ads&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Web video ads&lt;/li&gt;	
	&lt;li&gt;Promotional emails&lt;/li&gt;	
	&lt;li&gt;Referrals from another site&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Paid and organic search&lt;/li&gt;	
	&lt;li&gt;Social media&lt;/li&gt;	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime you rely on multiple strategies to help drive traffic through a funnel on your site, you're using a multi-channel funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What can I learn from a multi-channel funnel report?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several aspects to a multi-channel funnel that you may want to pay attention to when figuring out the value of each channel to your site. Different companies will place importance on each of these aspects differently depending on their use-case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/multi-channel-funnel-anatomy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics multi-channel funnel overview&quot; title=&quot;Anatomy of a conversion path - Taken from Google Analytics&quot; width=&quot;469px&quot; height=&quot;184px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;h3&gt;Last Interactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The channel that drove a user to your site right before they completed a conversion funnel is flagged as a 'last interaction' channel. If a marketing effort has a high percentage of last interactions, it's helping to close the deal with your users. While this is the initial place most companies look when assessing the value of their marketing efforts, it doesn't paint the full picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First Interactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By discovering what is driving a user to visit your site for the first time, you can discover which marketing efforts are helping spread initial awareness or interest about your brand. This will not allow you to easily differentiate between users who are just hearing about your site and users who have heard about it before and who simply saw something new that was convincing enough to check out your site. However, the value in either case is that a channel with a high percent of first interactions is clearly successful at driving initial interest in your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Assisted Interactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both the first and last interactions are key conversions points, any channel along the way that engages the user will get credit for an 'assisted conversion'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many marketing efforts that have a seemingly-low return on investment (ROI) can actually turn out to be fairly important. You may have an email campaign you use to nudge new users to offer them help as they learn more about your site or product. This email itself may not convert a lot of users and it won't be how they discover your site, but noting that this effort assists in a lot of conversions will help identify whether this nudge email is truly succeeding at nudging users along your conversion funnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Popular Conversion Paths&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report will show which paths of first, assisted, and last conversions are responsible for converting the most users. While this information can be useful, the utility is somewhat limited. It helps to visualize channel funnels from a high level, but most of the actions you take will be related to first, last, and assisted conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Time Through Path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to assess the success of marketing efforts is how much time passed between a user's first interaction and last interaction to conversion. You can use it to assess whether your efforts are resulting in people making decisions quickly. If you see that users are taking their time, you can use this information to experiment with ways to speed up their decision-making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How can I customize this report with my marketing channels in mind?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default channels make a few assumptions about how you tag your marketing campaigns. When your existing tags don't match those assumptions, it can create a rather messy report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/multi-channel-funnel-duplication.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics default channel grouping issues&quot; title=&quot;Well, that's repetitively redundant.&quot; width=&quot;534px&quot; height=&quot;109px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, Google Analytics allows you to override their default grouping and fix any issues you're encountering. You can do this through the admin menus, but I recommend starting by copying their default and editing it to meet your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To copy the default grouping, click on &quot;Channel Groupings&quot; in the menu above the &quot;Assisted Conversions&quot; report and select &quot;Copy Basic Channel Grouping template...&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/multi-channel-funnel-channel-grouping.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics channel grouping menu &quot; title=&quot;Channel Grouping menu&quot; width=&quot;787px&quot; height=&quot;114px&quot;/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, you can give your new template a name. then, hover over any of the &quot;Label Rules&quot; to get an option to edit. This will allow you to see what rules are used to create these groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/multi-channel-funnel-social-media-channel-default-filter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics social network channel default filter&quot; title=&quot;What a difference one character can make.&quot; width=&quot;903px&quot; height=&quot;35px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my original example used an underscore (&quot;social_media&quot;) whereas Google Analytics uses dashes or spaces in its original filter. I can easily edit the filter to include my variant so all of my existing campaigns are caught by the &quot;Social Network&quot; channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This screen also allows you to add new filters. For example, if you had a mobile app that has several links to your site, you might tag your links with a utm_medium parameter set to &quot;mobile&quot;. Then, you can create a custom label rule to group all links with a utm_medium of &quot;mobile&quot; as a channel called &quot;Mobile App&quot;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/multi-channel-funnel-mobile-app-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics mobile app example&quot; title=&quot;Go back! I liked that channel!&quot; width=&quot;132px&quot; height=&quot;140px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armed with a report customized for your website, it's much easier to make informed decisions on which of your marketing efforts are working and which ones need improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;funnel-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Funnels&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Paths through your site whose ends are major conversion points. For example, a sign-up funnel would end with the user registering successfully on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;segment-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Segments&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Groups of similar users on your site. For example, you can segment all users who came to your site from a specific source or all uusers who performed a certain key action on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
				<published>2012-07-08 00:00:00 -0700</published>
				<link>http://min-maxing.com/blog/2012/07/08/multi-channel-funnels-in-google-analytics</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Using Analytics to Find Actionable Data</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Pageviews don't make a site successful, but it's usually the first thing you see when you look at an analytics dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/dashboard-top-level.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics top-level dashboard metrics: visits, unique visitors, pageviews, pages per visit, average visit duration, bounce rate, and percent of visits that are new visits&quot; title=&quot;That's... good, right?&quot; width=&quot;328px&quot; height=&quot;303px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;These stats are displayed so prominently that it's easy to think that they're &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#kpi-definition&quot;&gt;key performance indicators&lt;/a&gt; (KPIs), and many companies treat them as such. The problem is that these aren't true KPIs; They're vanity metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What are vanity metrics?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanity metrics are metrics whose changes don't directly correlate to increased &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#conversion-definition&quot;&gt;conversions&lt;/a&gt;. While they might look pretty, they're only important in that they are the core building blocks for the data you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to be analyzing. If you focus on vanity metrics, you cannot answer the questions you need to answer to make sure your site is healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why are vanity metrics dangerous to use as performance indicators?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose I told you that my eCommerce storefront had 5% more unique visitors last month. At a very high level, that sounds great. Now, suppose I told you that revenue dropped 2% last month. Suddenly, it doesn't sound so good. Why am I making less money with more users?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even focusing on overall revenue is dangerous. Suppose I said my storefront was making 5% more money. Cause for celebration? Not if I had 50% more new users during that period. Why did so many more new users result in such a low increase in revenue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these scenarios create more questions than answers. However, it's easy to dig past these vanity metrics and answer those questions with actionable metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What are actionable metrics?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actionable metrics answer specific questions about the performance of a site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Am I making money on my marketing efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Where are visitors dropping off before they convert?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is there something I can do to make fewer users drop off?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is likely to cause users to convert at a higher rate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that these questions all focus not just on raw numbers, but attempt to get answers that can result in direct action to improve the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous example, I mentioned a site that saw 50% more new visitors but only 5% increased revenue. To figure out why, a good step would be to see how those users progressed through the purchase &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#funnel-definition&quot;&gt;funnel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://min-maxing.com/assets/img/blog/2012-07/funnel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics example conversion funnel&quot; title=&quot;Come back! I have stuff!&quot; width=&quot;258px&quot; height=&quot;805px&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the problem in the example is a bit more clear. The ad landing page had a lot of traffic that never got to the product page. The product page was pretty successful in that most people added the product to the cart, but most of those people didn't follow through with the purchase. Armed with this kind of information, it's easy to identify part of the site that should be considered for &lt;a data-toggle=&quot;modal&quot; href=&quot;#split-testing-definition&quot;&gt;split-testing&lt;/a&gt;. With some tweaks, it's possible to reduce the friction of this funnel and end up with more sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll have to dig deeper for actionable metrics than you do for vanity metrics, but it's worth it. Fortunately, most modern web analytics solutions provide standard reports that help discover many common actionable metrics pretty quickly. For information that's specific to your organization, you can also create custom reports that you can refer back to for tracking the progress of important actionable metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;kpi-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Key Performance Indicators&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Metrics that are used to determine whether or not something is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;conversion-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Conversion&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Favorable actions, whether they be direct product purchases or other significant events such as user registrations.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;funnel-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Funnel&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Funnels are paths through your site whose ends are major conversion points. For example, a sign-up funnel would end with the user registering successfully on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;modal hide&quot; id=&quot;split-testing-definition&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-header&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;×&lt;/button&gt;
    	&lt;h3&gt;Split-testing&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;p&gt;Testing multiple versions of a page side-by-side by splitting visitors between the pages to see which one is most likely to convert a user.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-footer&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<published>2012-07-04 00:00:00 -0700</published>
				<link>http://min-maxing.com/blog/2012/07/04/using-analytics-to-find-actionable-data</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Turning Weight Loss into a Game</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Losing weight is not fun. At some level, you&amp;#39;re forced to remove parts of your diet and lifestyle that are familiar and comfortable. In their place, you adopt things that are boring and difficult. People who are successful at losing weight tend to find different ways to make the process interesting by finding a sport they like to play as part of their exercise or healthy foods they like to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while, I played basketball with friends and switched to some diet versions of foods I normally ate. This was enough to help me drop from my all-time high of 235 lbs. to 195 lbs. Then, my weight loss flat-lined. The problem was that I was still intaking enough calories that, even with the burn of exercise, I&amp;#39;d reached equilibrium with my metabolism. I needed to cut calories to get any further, and that seemed like a great way to annoy me and ultimately derail from my plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to get over this hump while making this next phase of my weight loss interesting enough to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my venture by finding answers to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How many calories equal 1 pound of fat?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 pound of fat represents 3,500 calories&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;. To lose a pound of fat, your body has to have a net loss of 3,500 calories over the course of a period of time. Spoken differently, you have to use 3,500 more calories than you ingested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How many calories do I burn a day?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question consists of two parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How many calories do I burn at rest?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;a title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basal_metabolic_rate&quot;&gt;Basal Metabolic Rate&lt;/a&gt; (BMR) is the rate at which you burn calories at rest. This differs from person-to-person, but fortunately you can use a &lt;a title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate Calculator - My Fitness Pal&quot; href=&quot;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/tools/bmr-calculator&quot;&gt;BMR calculator&lt;/a&gt; to figure out how many calories you burn in a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 198 pounds, I burned 1922 calories while at rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How many calories do I burn doing my normal daily activities?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a title=&quot;Harris Benedict Equation - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harris-Benedict_equation&quot;&gt;Harris Benedict Principle&lt;/a&gt; is a rough guideline for figuring out how many calories you burn performing your daily activities. While not an exact number, it will give you enough actionable information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table&quot;&gt;
	&lt;thead&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;Activity Level&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;Example&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;Calories Burned&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/thead&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Sedentary&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;desk job, no exercise&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate&quot;&gt;BMR&lt;/abbr&gt; x 1.2&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Light&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;regular walking, exercise 1-3 times a week&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate&quot;&gt;BMR&lt;/abbr&gt; x 1.375&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Moderate&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;somewhat physically-demanding job, exercise 3-5 times a week&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate&quot;&gt;BMR&lt;/abbr&gt; x 1.55&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Heavy&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;physically-demanding job or daily exercise&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate&quot;&gt;BMR&lt;/abbr&gt; x 1.725&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Very Heavy&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;physically-demanding job &amp; daily exercise&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Basal Metabolic Rate&quot;&gt;BMR&lt;/abbr&gt; x 1.9&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I burned 2306 calories in a day at 198 pounds while working a desk job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;At what point does weight loss become unhealthy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you intake a low amount of calories, you can trigger your body&amp;#39;s &lt;a title=&quot;Starvation Response - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starvation_response&quot;&gt;starvation response&lt;/a&gt;. This puts your body in a state where it breaks down non-fatty tissue. This not only makes it harder to lose weight, but it decreases your overall health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the starvation response, you should end up with a net caloric intake of around 20% lower than the number of the calories you normally burn in a day. For those with a higher percentage of body fat, this can go up to 30%&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up creating a profile at &lt;a title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot; href=&quot;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/&quot;&gt;My Fitness Pal&lt;/a&gt; to help calculate a healthy weight loss rate. As part of the process, the site had me enter my current and goal weights, and then gave me a per-day calorie goal. That number started out at 1640 calories per day, which is about 29% lower than may daily calorie burn. This equates to losing about 1.3 pounds a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How much should I weigh to be healthy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;a title=&quot;Body Mass Index - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Body_mass_index&quot;&gt;Body Mass Index&lt;/a&gt; is a measure of the amount of fat in your body. You can use a &lt;a title=&quot;BMI Calculator - Center for Disease Control and Prevention&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/healthyweight/assessing/bmi/adult_bmi/english_bmi_calculator/bmi_calculator.html&quot;&gt;BMI calculator&lt;/a&gt; to determine your BMI and see the normal range for a person of your height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a 6&amp;#39;1&quot; male, a healthy weight is between 140 and 190 pounds. I decided to split the difference and make 165 pounds my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a set of rules and numbers to work against suddenly made the concept a little more interesting to me. It was beginning to turn weight loss into a game. By using &lt;a title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot; href=&quot;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/&quot;&gt;My Fitness Pal&lt;/a&gt; (MFP) to track my caloric intake each day, I could see my daily progress toward my goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot;&gt;MFP&lt;/abbr&gt; has a large database of foods already entered by site administrators and users, so tracking most of what I ate at home and restaurants turned out to be pretty easy. Anything that was not in the database was easy to add through their interface. I ran into a few circumstances where I had to enter nutritional information into the site by copying values over from restaurant nutrition guides or healthy recipe sites, but even that was pretty easy. &lt;abbr title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot;&gt;MFP&lt;/abbr&gt; also allows users to group foods together as &quot;meals&quot;, so I could easily take the bread, mayo, cheese, and meat for my sandwiches and combine it into one &quot;meal&quot;. Then, I merely had to add a serving of that meal when I wanted to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I fell into the practice of eating the same healthy breakfast over and over, it became even easier. All I had to do was copy my &quot;breakfast&quot; menu from the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one case, my wife had a good recipe for a &lt;a title=&quot;Healthy Mexican Lasagna - eHow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ehow.com/how_5036990_make-healthy-mexican-lasagna.html&quot;&gt;healthy mexican lasagna&lt;/a&gt;, but no nutrition information for it. After entering the ingredients into a spreadsheet, however, I was able to calculate the nutrition content per serving. I entered that as a meal. Shortly thereafter, &lt;abbr title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot;&gt;MFP&lt;/abbr&gt; released a custom recipe feature that facilitated doing this without having to use separate spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I started tracking my caloric intake, I became fixated on other numbers. The Andriod application for &lt;abbr title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot;&gt;MFP&lt;/abbr&gt; allowed me to see how much of the various nutrients (fiber, potassium, sodium, various vitamins) I was intaking on a normal basis as well. I started structuring my diet to intake the proper amount of calories while ensuring I reached my good nutrient goals as well (ideally via food, but also via dietary supplements if I was under a vitamin goal for the day). Tracking the various numbers during this process was the final step in turning my weight loss goal into a game for me, and before I knew it I was well on my way to my goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking my protein and fiber intake proved to have an additional benefit: protien and fiber are great ways to make food &quot;stick with you&quot; (basically, keeping you feeling full for longer without artificial appetite suppressants).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning weight loss into a game was ultimately the change I needed in my diet plan to get me to reach my goal weight. The game became the core focus, and everything else I did (which normally would have felt like sacrifice) was a way of min-maxing my nutrient stats to win the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still ate out but I was able to find healthy alternatives that were pleasing without feeling like I was forcing myself to eat something I didn&amp;#39;t really like for the sake of health. The only time it got annoying was when I had to enter my chosen meal as a custom food in &lt;abbr title=&quot;My Fitness Pal&quot;&gt;MFP&lt;/abbr&gt; because it wasn&amp;#39;t already there, but that only happened occasionally, and even then it was only early-on, before I had entered all the foods I eat regularly when I eat out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did exercise a bit throughout this process, but it wasn&amp;#39;t the main factor in my weight loss. In fact, if I worked out during one day, it just meant that I had to eat more that day to make sure I kept above the level via which the starvation response was triggered. In the end, exercise was a great way to treat myself to a dessert or a less-healthy meal. Of course, working out is a very good addition to a weight loss plan for the other &lt;a title=&quot;Health Benefits of Physical Exercise - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physical_exercise#Benefits&quot;&gt;health benefits&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, different methods will work for different people with regard to losing weight. Physicians and personal trainers can offer better advice than most people (including myself) with regard to tailoring a healthy weight loss plan to your needs. If you can, though, find a way to merge it with one of your passions.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;Weight Gain - Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weight_gain#Simple_formula&quot;&gt;Weight Gain - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;5 Tips to Avoid Plateaus and Metabolic Slowdown - Fit Watch&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fitwatch.com/weight-loss/5-tips-to-avoid-plateaus-and-metabolic-slowdown-647.html&quot;&gt;5 Tips to Avoid Plateaus and Metabolic Slowdown - Fit Watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
				<published>2012-06-24 00:00:00 -0700</published>
				<link>http://min-maxing.com/blog/2012/06/24/losing-weight-for-geeks</link>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
